School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Pullman, Washington, 99163 alaleh.github.io a.ahmadianshalchi@wsu.edu Phone: (206) 288-9851

## RESEARCH SUMMARY

My general research interests are in Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), and Sequential Decision-making under Uncertainty with applications to real-world problems in engineering and scientific domains. My current research focuses on developing fast and effective Bayesian Optimization (BO) methods and applying them to real-world problems to accelerate hardware design and 3D printing of biomedical structures.

#### EDUCATION

### Washington State University, Pullman, WA

Fall 2019 -

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science

Advisor: Prof. Jana Doppa

Research Topic: Use-Inspired Bayesian Optimization for Science and Engineering Applications

### Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

2014 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Research Topic: Design and development of scalable algorithms for graph-matching in large ridesharing networks

### Professional Experience

Research Assistant, Washington State University, EECS

Aug 2019 – Present

Teaching Assistant, Washington State University, EECS

Aug 2019 - Present

CptS 570: Machine Learning (Fall 2022)

CptS 415: Big Data (Fall 2021)

CptS 223: Advanced Data Structures (Fall 2020)

CptS 350: Design and Analysis of Algorithms (Spring 2020)

Machine Learning Engineering Intern, Rahnema Co, Tehran, Iran Dec 2018 – Mar 2019 **Description**: Developing a recommendation system for online shopping websites based on deep learning methods.

Teaching Assistant, Sharif University of Technology, CS-Math

Fall 2015 – Fall 2018

CS22014: Introduction To Programming(Java) (Fall 2018)

CS22891: Design and Analysis of Algorithms (Spring 2017)

CS22822: Data Structure Design (Fall 2016)

CE22013: Introduction To Programming(C/C++) (Fall 2015)

Front-End Web Development Intern, Chi Co, Tehran, Iran

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

**Description:** Front-End design and development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Bootstrap

Algorithm Design and C++ Programming Instructor, Farzanegan Highschool, Mashhad, Iran

June 2014 – Sept 2014

**Description**: Teaching algorithm Design and C++ programming in classes for National Olympiad in informatics (INOI).

#### SKILLS

- Python, R, SQL, MATLAB, C, C++, Java
- Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Mathematical Modeling, Statistical Modeling, Algorithm Analysis, Data structures, Discrete Mathematics, Graph Theory, Statistics, and Problem Solving theoretically and

Alaleh Ahmadian Curriculum Vitae 1 of 4

practically

- Web development (Django, Python, CSS, HTML, JS, VueJS),
- LATEX, Linux, Bash, git

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- A. Ahmadianshalchi, S. Belakaria, and J. Doppa **Adaptive Diversity-Aware Batch Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization**. Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2023. Under review.
- A. Ahmadianshalchi, S. Belakaria, Z. Zhou, J. Doppa, and D. Heo. **Design Automation of Analog Circuits via Information-Theoretic Optimization**. *IEEE Design and Test of Computers*, 2022. Under review.
- Z. Zhou\*, A. Ahmadianshalchi\*, S. Belakaria, J. Doppa, and D. Heo. Multi-Output Switched-Capacitor Converter Design Optimization via Machine Learning. *IEEE Design and Test of Computers*, 2022. Under review.
- A. Ahmadianshalchi, S. Belakaria, J. Doppa Preference-Aware Constrained Multi-Objective Bayesian Optimization for Analog Circuit Design: An Information-Theoretic Approach. Workshop on ML for Systems at Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- A. Ahmadianshalchi, A. Deshwal, C. Simon, and J. Doppa. Bayesian Optimization for Design of Metal-organic Frameworks. (In preparation)

## Academic Projects

## Machine Learning to Optimize 3D Printing,

Dec 2021 – Present

Description: Designing a multi-objective Bayesian Optimization method to optimize 3D printing of body parts

## Bayesian Optimization to Accelerate Hardware Design,

Aug 2021 – Present

Description: Designing a robust Bayesian Optimization method to optimize a high conversion ratio converter's efficiency as well as settling time. Paper to be submitted to TVLSI journal.

## Bayesian Optimization for Metal-Organic Frameworks,

July 2021 - Present

Description: Design a multi-objective Bayesian optimization algorithm to select optimal metalorganic framework (MOF) structures from a library of materials for hydrogen-powered vehicles. Paper to be submitted to Chemistry journal.

# ${\bf Ride\text{-}Sharing\ graph\ matching},$

Oct 2018 - May 2019

Description: Developing a scalable algorithm to find the most efficient matching for a ride sharing system in a mega city network graph.

### News Sentiment Analysis.

Jan 2018 – July 2018

Description: Using sentiment analysis to Find the relationship between fake news and its prominent attributes in order to classify news sources that are mostly fake and predict the type of news(fake, true, misleading,...).

## AWARDS AND HONORS

Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award from Voiland College of Engineering Washington State University

2022

Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award from EECS Department Washington State University

2022

Selected amongst the top 40 people from 1800 candidates through three rounds of exams for Rahnema College ML internship 2018

Ranked in the first 0.5% (791 out of 191,551 participants) in the national university entrance exam (Math and Physics major)

Ranked in the first 0.1% (122 out of 99,104 participants) in the national university entrance exam (English Literature major)

### CERTIFICATIONS

- TOEFL IBT: 110/120 (Reading: 26/30, Listening: 30/30, Speaking: 27/30, Writing: 27/30)
- General GRE: Quantitative Reasoning: 170/170, Verbal Reasoning: 149/170, Analytical Writing: 4.5/6

## Relevant Coursework

## Toward PhD Degree at Washington State University

- CPTS 570 Machine Learning
- CPTS 534 Neural Network Design and Applications
- CPTS 575 Data Science
- CPTS 571 Computational Genomics
- CPTS 515 Advanced Algorithms
- CPTS 583 Software Quality
- CPTS 415 Big Data

#### MISCELLANEOUS

#### **External Conference Reviewer**

- AAAI 2023
- AAAI Workshop on AI to Accelerate Science and Engineering-2022

## Technical/Professional Events

- Selected to Participate in Meetings for Professional Growth
  - CRA-WP Graduate Cohort for Women, 2020
  - CRA-WP Graduate Cohort for Women, 2021
  - CRA-WP Graduate Cohort for Women, 2022
- Presentations/Talks
  - SRC TechCon 2022 Presenting our work on "Preference-Aware Bayesian Optimization to Accelerate Hardware Design".
- Volunteer Work
  - Women in Machine Learning (WiML) Workshop, NeurIPS 2022
  - ICML 2022
  - Women in Machine Learning (WiML) Workshop, NeurIPS 2021

## LANGUAGES

• Persian: Native

• English: Professional

• Arabic: Limited Working Proficiency

• French: Limited Working Proficiency

# REFERENCES

 Prof. Jana Doppa George and Joan Berry Distinguished Associate Professor School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Email: jana.doppa@wsu.edu

• Prof. Partha Pande Boeing Centennial Chair Professor School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Email: pande@wsu.edu